<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title>article on Hydro-Blogger | Saswata Nandi's Hydrology Blog</title><link>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/article/</link><description>Recent content in article on Hydro-Blogger | Saswata Nandi's Hydrology Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>withsaswata@gmail.com (Dr. Saswata Nandi)</managingEditor><webMaster>withsaswata@gmail.com (Dr. Saswata Nandi)</webMaster><copyright>&amp;copy;{year}, All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 14:08:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/article/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automatic model calibration</title><link>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/article/h20_2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>withsaswata@gmail.com (Dr. Saswata Nandi)</author><atom:modified>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</atom:modified><guid>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/article/h20_2020/</guid><description>Recently, physically-based hydrological models have been gaining much popularity in various activities of water resources planning and management, such as assessment of basin water availability, floods, droughts, and reservoir operation. Every hydrological model contains some parameters that must be tuned to the catchment being studied to obtain reliable estimates from the model. This study evaluated the performance of different evolutionary algorithms, namely genetic algorithm (GA), shuffled complex evolution (SCE), differential evolution (DE), and self-adaptive differential evolution (SaDE) algorithm for the parameter calibration of a computationally intensive distributed hydrological model, variable infiltration capacity (VIC) model.</description><dc:creator>Dr. Saswata Nandi</dc:creator></item><item><title>Water budget and climate change</title><link>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/article/wrm_2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>withsaswata@gmail.com (Dr. Saswata Nandi)</author><atom:modified>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</atom:modified><guid>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/article/wrm_2020/</guid><description>Quantification of water-budget components is an essential step in the planning andmanagement of water resources in any river basin. Recently several studies emphasizedthat climate change would inevitably affect terrestrial hydrology. This study appliesdistributed hydrological modeling using the Variable Infiltration Capacity (VIC) modelto simulate the water balance components in the Sina basin, a drought-prone region inIndia. We analyzed the long-term spatiotemporal dynamics of precipitation, evapotrans-piration, surface runoff, and baseflow components, and their alterations due to impendingclimate change.</description><dc:creator>Dr. Saswata Nandi</dc:creator></item><item><title>Hydrological modelling over Krishna basin</title><link>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/article/ewra_2017/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>withsaswata@gmail.com (Dr. Saswata Nandi)</author><atom:modified>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</atom:modified><guid>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/article/ewra_2017/</guid><description>Floods can have catastrophic consequences and can have effects on the economy, environment and people. It initiates comprehensive assessment and forecasting of possible flooding events, which is typically carried out using hydrological models. Thus, the main objective of this study was to present a distributed hydrological model, namely Variable Infiltration Capacity (VIC) model for simulating the hydrological variables over Krishna River Basin, India and evaluating its performance by comparing with observed datasets.</description><dc:creator>Dr. Saswata Nandi</dc:creator></item></channel></rss>