<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title>article on Hydro-Blogger | Saswata Nandi's Hydrology Blog</title><link>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/article/</link><description>Recent content in article on Hydro-Blogger | Saswata Nandi's Hydrology Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>withsaswata@gmail.com (Saswata Nandi)</managingEditor><webMaster>withsaswata@gmail.com (Saswata Nandi)</webMaster><copyright>&amp;copy;{year}, All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 14:08:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/article/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Heatwave analysis over south Indian cities</title><link>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/article/espr_2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>withsaswata@gmail.com (Saswata Nandi)</author><atom:modified>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</atom:modified><guid>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/article/espr_2022/</guid><description>Climate change is arguably the most alarming global concern of the twenty-first century, particularly due to the increased frequency of meteorological extremes, e.g., heatwaves, droughts, and floods. Heatwaves are considered a potential health risk and urge further study, robust preparedness, and policy framing. This study presents an analysis of heatwave characteristics for historical (1980–2014), near-future (2021–2055), and far-future (2056–2090) scenarios over three highly populated cities of South India, i.e., Bangalore, Chennai, and Hyderabad.</description><dc:creator>Saswata Nandi</dc:creator></item><item><title>Hydrological utility of LSTM-corrected IMERG</title><link>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/article/gc_2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>withsaswata@gmail.com (Saswata Nandi)</author><atom:modified>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</atom:modified><guid>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/article/gc_2022/</guid><description>In this study, the performance and hydrological utility of IMERG rainfall estimates over the Upper Bhima River basin, India, are comprehensively evaluated using a VIC-RAPID hydrologic model. Moreover, a bias-correction scheme based on the long short-term memory (LSTM) neural network method is proposed, and the results are compared with two commonly used bias-correction techniques. Results indicated that the spatial distribution of observed rainfall is well captured by IMERG; however, it showed a general tendency of overestimation, especially on a daily timescale.</description><dc:creator>Saswata Nandi</dc:creator></item><item><title>Integrated flood modelling system</title><link>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/article/joh_2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>withsaswata@gmail.com (Saswata Nandi)</author><atom:modified>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</atom:modified><guid>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/article/joh_2022/</guid><description>Controlling the damaging effects of fluvial flood events has been a major challenge for mankind. Integrated hydrologic-hydrodynamic models are often employed to estimate the flow and vital flood inundation information for mitigating such damages. The most important criterion for their implementation is that they should offer large-scale applicability with a finer resolution to have local relevance and practicability. This study presented an integrated modeling framework, VIC-RAPID-LISFP that couples a hydrological model (VIC), a river routing model (RAPID) and a hydrodynamic model (LISFLOOD-FP) for fast generation of high-resolution flow and flood inundation extent.</description><dc:creator>Saswata Nandi</dc:creator></item><item><title>Automatic model calibration</title><link>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/article/h20_2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>withsaswata@gmail.com (Saswata Nandi)</author><atom:modified>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</atom:modified><guid>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/article/h20_2020/</guid><description>Recently, physically-based hydrological models have been gaining much popularity in various activities of water resources planning and management, such as assessment of basin water availability, floods, droughts, and reservoir operation. Every hydrological model contains some parameters that must be tuned to the catchment being studied to obtain reliable estimates from the model. This study evaluated the performance of different evolutionary algorithms, namely genetic algorithm (GA), shuffled complex evolution (SCE), differential evolution (DE), and self-adaptive differential evolution (SaDE) algorithm for the parameter calibration of a computationally intensive distributed hydrological model, variable infiltration capacity (VIC) model.</description><dc:creator>Saswata Nandi</dc:creator></item><item><title>Water budget and climate change</title><link>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/article/wrm_2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>withsaswata@gmail.com (Saswata Nandi)</author><atom:modified>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</atom:modified><guid>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/article/wrm_2020/</guid><description>Quantification of water-budget components is an essential step in the planning andmanagement of water resources in any river basin. Recently several studies emphasizedthat climate change would inevitably affect terrestrial hydrology. This study appliesdistributed hydrological modeling using the Variable Infiltration Capacity (VIC) modelto simulate the water balance components in the Sina basin, a drought-prone region inIndia. We analyzed the long-term spatiotemporal dynamics of precipitation, evapotrans-piration, surface runoff, and baseflow components, and their alterations due to impendingclimate change.</description><dc:creator>Saswata Nandi</dc:creator></item><item><title>Hydrological modelling over Krishna basin</title><link>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/article/ewra_2017/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>withsaswata@gmail.com (Saswata Nandi)</author><atom:modified>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</atom:modified><guid>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/article/ewra_2017/</guid><description>Floods can have catastrophic consequences and can have effects on the economy, environment and people. It initiates comprehensive assessment and forecasting of possible flooding events, which is typically carried out using hydrological models. Thus, the main objective of this study was to present a distributed hydrological model, namely Variable Infiltration Capacity (VIC) model for simulating the hydrological variables over Krishna River Basin, India and evaluating its performance by comparing with observed datasets.</description><dc:creator>Saswata Nandi</dc:creator></item></channel></rss>