<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title>book on Hydro-Blogger | Saswata Nandi's Hydrology Blog</title><link>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/book/</link><description>Recent content in book on Hydro-Blogger | Saswata Nandi's Hydrology Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>snandi4@ucmerced.edu (Saswata Nandi)</managingEditor><webMaster>snandi4@ucmerced.edu (Saswata Nandi)</webMaster><copyright>&amp;copy;{year}, All Rights Reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 14:08:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Efficient calibration of a macroscale hydrological model</title><link>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/book/picsnc_2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>snandi4@ucmerced.edu (Saswata Nandi)</author><atom:modified>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</atom:modified><guid>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/book/picsnc_2021/</guid><description>Physically based distributed hydrological models are an invaluable tool for planning and management of water resource projects. However, a reliable prediction from hydrological models can only be expected if their unknown model parameters are estimated accurately. In place of laborious manual calibration of the parameters of the hydrological model, this study presents an automatic calibration scheme for the VIC-RAPID hydrological model using the self-adaptive differential evolution (SaDE) algorithm. The SaDE eliminates the laborious manual tuning of the two control parameters (mutation factor and crossover rate) of the conventional DE algorithm.</description><dc:creator>Saswata Nandi</dc:creator></item><item><title>Multi-objective calibration of VIC-RAPID using MOSADE</title><link>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/book/cciwr_2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>snandi4@ucmerced.edu (Saswata Nandi)</author><atom:modified>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</atom:modified><guid>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/book/cciwr_2021/</guid><description>The physically based hydrological models require the estimation of various model parameters through calibration. Several past studies that focused on parameter estimation of hydrological models have found that no single objective performance criterion is adequate for matching different essential characteristics of the observation data. Since physically based hydrological models simulate many of the catchment hydrological processes, it needs to define multiple performance criteria to effectively use the information from various datasets and application of multiobjective optimization for attaining Pareto optimal solutions.</description><dc:creator>Saswata Nandi</dc:creator></item><item><title>SaDE based automatic calibration of VIC-RAPID integrated model</title><link>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/book/wmwg_2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>snandi4@ucmerced.edu (Saswata Nandi)</author><atom:modified>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</atom:modified><guid>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/book/wmwg_2021/</guid><description>To overcome the drawbacks faced by the traditional manual calibration of hydrological models, this study employs an adaptive differential evolution (DE) algorithm for automatic calibration of Variable Infiltration Capacity (VIC) hydrological model. In the DE algorithm, proper tuning of its control parameters is laborious and generally needs a great amount of time and resources. Therefore, a self-adaptive scheme is presented to enhance the efficacy of the basic DE. The proposed automatic parameter estimation scheme is applied for a case study and evaluated its performance using standard performance measures of coefficient of correlation (R2), Nash–Sutcliffe coefficient (NSE), percent bias (PBIAS), and index of agreement (IoA).</description><dc:creator>Saswata Nandi</dc:creator></item><item><title>ARIMA-based forecasting of monthly precipitation</title><link>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/book/rfict_2018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>snandi4@ucmerced.edu (Saswata Nandi)</author><atom:modified>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</atom:modified><guid>https://saswatanandi.github.io/publication/book/rfict_2018/</guid><description>The assessment of climate change, especially in terms of rainfall variability, is of giant concern all over the world at present. Contemplating the high spatiotemporal variation in rainfall distribution, the prior estimation of precipitation is necessary at finer scales too. This study aims to develop an ARIMA model for prediction of monthly rainfall over Khordha district, Odisha, India. Due to the unavailability of recent rainfall data, monthly rainfall records were collected for 1901–2002.</description><dc:creator>Saswata Nandi</dc:creator></item></channel></rss>